China was had by far and away the most
hash rate in the world. When China
banned Bitcoin mining a number of years
ago, a lot of the Chinese miners
relocated to the US. Historically, we've
been able to mine Bitcoin between 20 and
$40,000 each. Companies that don't sell
their Bitcoin have no other choice but
to dilute the shares. So, they're equity
funded. Is it really worth that much of
a premium? There's power that isn't
always consumed. And if you don't
consume it, you lose it. It goes to
ground. You can't store it. Think of a
Bitcoin miner as kind of a battery where
they overbuild generation to feed the
massive demand for AI. But when the AI
isn't demanding the power, you got the
surplus capacity that has to go
somewhere. And Bitcoin mining is an
interruptible load. Now, they're
speculating that if Bitcoin passes
certain thresholds, there are
liquidations, forced liquidations
that'll take place that could drive the
price of Bitcoin parabolic with that
much demand pent up on the network. And
supply being fixed, doesn't matter if
Bitcoin goes to 300,000. We can't mine
more than 450 Bitcoin a day, no matter
what. The supply shock, in my mind, is
what's really going to drive that next
phase. I firmly believe that Bitcoin
will exceed. miners hold absolute power
over the Bitcoin price. Meaning, you
said there are only 450 Bitcoin mined a
day. What you can do is I'll just hold
it.
>> Why are you guys manipulating the price
of Bitcoin? All of the Bitcoin miners
are going to get together and say,
"Okay, guys, on three, we're going to
hold all the Bitcoin." And
what is the future of mining, not just
in America, but around the world?
Bitcoin miner uh CleanSpark is here with
us and executive chairman Matt Schultz
will give us his breakdown on his
outlook for Bitcoin mining Bitcoin
overall and his guidance on CleanSpark
operations for the remainder of the
year. I'm David Lynn
>> Bonnie Chang.
>> Thank you for joining us Matt.
>> Thank you for having me. Uh before we
talk about operations, let's talk about
Bitcoin mining in general. Because
retails investors, they're like miners
sound like they have this absolute power
over the Bitcoin price, especially
around having we hear this narrative
that miners will hold the supply and not
sell because you know your salary
so-called will be cut in half and if you
don't sell then maybe the price will 1x
and at least you'll stay even.
>> So it's an interesting concept but it's
a bit of a fallacy. So, Bitcoin is
hardcapped. So, that means there will
only ever be 21 million Bitcoin. And
there are currently 20 million
outstanding. So, there's there's almost
20 million. So, there's not a long ways
to go. So, to think that um you know, if
we were to back up a little bit and look
at the block reward after the having
last May, the the global block reward
has dropped to 450 Bitcoin. So, there's
only 450 new Bitcoin a day regardless of
how many miners. So the more miners that
are on the network, the more difficult
it is for us to win a block and to mine
Bitcoin. So that number doesn't change
based on a miner's output or anything
like that. So the idea that we control
supply is kind of a misnomer.
My company um we had from back in 2023,
we kept 100% of the Bitcoin that we
mined and we added those to our balance
sheet. The reason was that companies
like Micro Strategy that are now buying
hundreds of thousands of Bitcoin,
they're paying H1, $108, $110,000.
Historically, we've been able to mine
Bitcoin between 20 and $40,000 each. So,
it just makes sense to add that to our
balance sheet because it is such a
scarce asset.
>> And um I saw one of your interviews you
said your Bitcoin yield is 2 to 3% a
week. So yeah, that I want to correct or
or clarify that. So
this earlier this year, we shifted our
strategy. So a lot of Bitcoin miners pay
for their operating expenses and their
growth by selling shares of stock. So if
you're a retail investor and the company
is going through a constant dilution
cycle, it makes it difficult to realize
appreciation and the value of the
shares. So, CleanSpark made a pivot
where we sell a portion of our Bitcoin
to cover the opex and then we use a line
of credit that's secured by our other
bitcoin to make new acquisitions. So,
for capex, so
the idea is that we can more efficiently
operate our business by selling some of
that production. Well, if we know we're
going to sell production, we then add a
little bit of juice to that by writing
um derivative contracts. So, if I'm
planning to sell half my production
anyway, we write 5day future contracts.
So, we generate a margin or they pay us
a premium to write those derivative
contracts that are 1 2 3 4% just for a
5day contract. So, at the end of that,
we get the Bitcoin called away that we
were going to sell anyway, plus we get
the premium on that. So that's where
that number came from. I I don't mean to
imply that it's, you know, 120%
annualized, but there are yields that
come from these weekly transactions that
add value to CleanSpark for Bitcoin we
plan to sell anyway.
>> So you said there's going to be constant
dilution without the system. Why would
there be dilution for miners overall?
>> So if you if if you have a 100% hddle
strategy,
>> yeah,
>> your your generation of revenue comes
from the Bitcoin that you mine. But if
you keep it all, how do you make money?
And so most of our peers, if you look at
any of the other major companies, they
all put up a recently two of our peers
have put up $2 billion ATM offering. So
it's an at the market, which means they
do a shelf registration and they have
shares of stock available that based on
their needs, they can push those shares
into the market. So it dilutes the
balance of the shareholders. It it's
kind of counterintuitive to a normal
business where you build a widget and
you sell a widget and you make margin.
That's how you're profitable. Well, if
you build widgets and you hold all of
those widgets never to sell them, how do
you fund the growth of your company? How
do you pay how do you pay your payroll?
How do you pay your utilities? So,
companies that don't sell their Bitcoin
have no other choice but to dilute the
shares. So, they're equity funded. And
if you have a constant cycle of equity
funding and you're an investor, it makes
it difficult to know, you know, if there
if there's an an endless supply of
shares, it makes it difficult for the
share price to go up. So the way we look
at it, you know, back in the 70s, the US
government deped the dollar from gold.
What that meant is now there's no hard
cap on it because it's not tied to gold.
So we can just print more. We print
more, the dollar becomes worth less,
inflation goes crazy, we have all kinds
of geopolitical issues as a result of
currency devaluation.
Bitcoin mining companies that operate on
this endless dilution cycle are
basically the same thing. They they've
removed the underpinning value and they
just use shares to do everything from
growth to opex to capex to bonuses to
whatever the case may be. We feel like
there's a better way to do it. And you
know, quite frankly, the feedback from
the sellside analysts on Wall Street is
that our strategy is the more adult in
the room kind of strategy. So we wear
that kind of as a badge of honor.
>> So these companies that you talked
about, they measure in BPS, Bitcoin per
share, and you measure in EPS, I assume.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
so what is your view on this BPS um new
metric? Like if there are two types of
company, one you measure in BPS, the
other one you measure in EPS, is that
fair?
>> Sure. Um it's just a different it's a
different perspective. So the the whole
idea of yield generation and sats per
share kind of originated with Michael
Sailor. Um the idea that you know
they're a Bitcoin treasury company. um
and and the appreciation of Bitcoin
theoretically increases the value of the
SATs per share in the company. The
inverse of that is if you're continually
printing new shares of stock, that
number changes all the time, much the
same way that earnings per share would.
The challenge is that when companies
when when Bitcoin has a down cycle and
it pulls back in price like the first
quarter this year and companies are
continuing to use equity to fund now
you're increasing the number of shares
and you're decreasing the value of the
Bitcoin so that BPS becomes a negative
number and in the Bitcoin mining space
it's such a nent field I mean nobody's a
second generation Bitcoin miner because
it's only been around 15 16 years right
so the idea that, you know, this is a
metric that we want to plant our flag
and we're going to be measured by the
Bitcoin yield. Well, then when that
becomes a negative number, a lot of the
miners conveniently remove that from
their monthly updates. And so, we don't
feel like it's the most transparent way
to communicate with our shareholders. We
we want to be really transparent about
our energy costs, about our cost of
mine, about our efficiency. And we think
earnings per share is the most
fundamental measurement of how we're
performing as a company.
>> CleanSpark doesn't just hodddle though.
you do sell some Bitcoin on occasion for
liquidity needs. So, for example,
correct me if I'm wrong, but I believe
Clean Clean Spark sold roughly 400 401
Bitcoin uh during the month of April. Um
how do you balance hodling versus
selling for liquidity?
>> So, this what we sell is to cover all of
our operating expenses. So, if you think
about what the opex necessary to operate
a Bitcoin mining company, you're talking
about personnel. So the the labor costs,
the energy costs, um insurance,
infrastructure overhead, all the
different things that are required.
Rather than diluting our shareholders
and selling equity, we're now selling
some of that hodddle. Actually, I want
to correct that. We don't sell our
hodddle, we sell production. So the
hodddle is old dated Bitcoin. And the
reason we don't want to sell it is
because we mined it at $20,000 a coin.
So there's a big tax impact if we were
to sell that. So what we are selling is
the Bitcoin that or a portion of the
Bitcoin that we're mining on a monthly
basis to prevent equity dilution
pressure.
>> Just as a followup, let's say
hypothetically I were an investor and I
were to say to you, why not sell all
your Bitcoin as a strategy, issue that
all in dividends is in the form of fiat
cash and I will use that cash to buy my
own Bitcoin.
>> Yeah, that's a great argument and I I
think the counterpoint is if you want to
buy Bitcoin, buy Bitcoin. a minor that's
really efficient, a company like Clean
Spark that our most recent quarter we
disclosed that it cost us about $42,000
to mine a bitcoin. If you're looking for
an investment in the space that is a
proxy for Bitcoin that gives you kind of
a leverage play, that's why we think
CleanSpark has appeal by maintaining a
portion of that Bitcoin on our balance
sheet that we mind at a fraction of the
spot price versus buying Bitcoin at spot
or buying a Bitcoin holding company that
they go borrow money or dilute shares
and they just buy the Bitcoin at market.
I mean, the fundamental question is
this. Why is a Bitcoin on Michael
Sailor's balance sheet worth three times
more than you can buy a Bitcoin for
today? And the, you know, the answer is
that it's a leverage play and that, you
know, his his strategy of Bitcoin yield
is different than you're going to get
from buying and owning the Bitcoin, but
is it really worth that much of a
premium? So, we think that by having a
blended approach covering our opex
through the sale of some of the Bitcoin,
but still giving our investors exposure
to the Bitcoin that we hodddle,
although, you know, we have 12,500
Bitcoin and we've paid a fraction of
spot price for those because we mined
them all at our own sites by our own
employees. So, it's it's more of a
leverage play for us. I think a lot of
investors assume when Bitcoin hits
all-time high, all the Bitcoin related
companies should hit all-time high as
well. Can you comment on that?
>> Yeah, so it's it's interesting when
there was a lack of volatility and
liquidity in the space. Bitcoin would go
up and the the the miners were really
the only proxy. You know, you think back
to the last presidential administration.
Banks couldn't custody Bitcoin. Um,
Bitcoin was forbidden for use in a
multitude of different arenas. And not
only that, there was a an an incident
during the Biden administration where
they literally debanked American
companies that had a touch point with
Bitcoin. So, you have a a a commodity, a
basically a a currency that's legal for
use. But the government had this
initiative to make it difficult. They
wanted to ban Bitcoin in the United
States. They wanted to push it all
offshore. So the challenge is that how
how do you how do you invest in Bitcoin
without investing in Bitcoin because
there were institutional investors that
couldn't buy Bitcoin and there were no
Bitcoin ETFs at the time. So Bitcoin
went up, Bitcoin miners went up because
we were an adjacent investment or proxy,
if you will. Well, now that the ETFs are
out there, if you want to buy exposure
to a Bitcoin, you can buy a Bitcoin ETF.
You can buy a leveraged ETF. You can buy
a short ETF. So for a proxy investment,
those those ETFs have garnered a lot of
of focus. Then you have the Bitcoin
treasury companies that go out and
borrow money, buy Bitcoin, hold it on
their balance sheet. So what happens is
when hedge funds buy those those
issuers, they generally pair those
trades. So they go long a bit Bitcoin
treasury company and to balance that
trade or to hedge it, they go short
another related but not directly related
investment. So you look at what would be
a proxy to Bitcoin that you could go
short that has a lot of liquidity and a
lot of volatility because that's where
equities are valued, right? So Bitcoin
miners, I mean you look at a company
like CleanSpark, we trade 4500 million a
day in equity. So there's a ton of
liquidity. Um, and it makes sense to to
use that as the short side of a pair
trade. Now, that only makes sense until
such time that there's an inflow of
buying. So, we look at the current
status, the current environment where
there's a a very heavy short position in
Clean Spark stock. It's a negative
because it's holding the share price
down. It doesn't matter to us right now
because we're not using equity to do
anything. So we we have the patience and
the ability to out to wait out the short
sellers because as we continue to
improve, we've messaged to the market
that we'll hit 50x a hash this summer.
um when it comes to market dynamics and
and specific um
specific points that we monitor very
closely um efficiency of the fleet um
total Bitcoin production um energy cost
the amount of Bitcoin that we hodddle
all of those criteria that you know
critical critical points that we monitor
very closely give us the the flexibility
I guess to remain profitable without
putting pressure on our shares. So
ultimately, as many of our peers are
pivoting away from Bitcoin, they're
going to a hybrid. They're doing AI,
they're doing different other types of
business with the megawatts, CleanSpark
is the last remaining pure play minor.
And we believe and a lot of the feedback
that we've had based on institutional
investment is that that's that's a a
strategy that's favored by the
institutional investors on Wall Street.
We've we had 10% institutional holding
just three short years ago and now it's
close to 70%. So the you know if you
watch the movie Dumb Money the
institutions think they're the smart
money. So the smart money has really
started to kind of ape into clean spark
stock because of the fact that we've
very disciplined pure play strategy and
we've our our capital management or
capital stewardship I think is second to
none in the space.
for
Google.
Elsa speak.
Fore.
Well, I really appreciate that you
answer these questions. I appreciate
your kind words.
Speech analyzer.
Bonnie,
Elsa Pro, Elsa Premium.
Um I had Samong Mao Gen 3 um founder on
the show and he was telling me that you
know after all Bitcoin are mined um of
course we have transaction fee but um
energy companies and Bitcoin miners will
become the same company. Can you tell us
how that works? Yeah. So, um, I just
finished a panel and one of the things
we talked about on the panel was
revitalizing rural communities through
Bitcoin mining. So, you think about in
the United States when the utility grid
was laid out. So, we we do business in
Georgia, Tennessee, Mississippi,
Wyoming, um, more rural states. And when
the utility grid was laid out four,
five, six decades ago in this country,
there was a lot more industry. There was
mining, there was manufacturing, timber
mills. Um, in Georgia specifically,
there were a lot of textile
manufacturers. There's more carpet made
in the state of Georgia than any
anywhere else in the world. Well, as
many of those industries have offshored,
you've got these little communities that
are left with pockets of power that the
cities created the municipal bonds to
buy the generation that they now own the
power and the business has gone away.
Um, one of the things I mentioned on my
panel, you know, I'm I'm a dad, so my
kids watch the movie Cars. So, the the
story about the little town Radiator
Springs, right? Bustling town, cool
stuff going on, and the interstate comes
by and the town gets forgotten. It's
much the same way in rural America. As
jobs and industry have gone offshore or
moved elsewhere, you got these little
towns that have abundant power and a
workforce that would like to stay home,
but no opportunities. So what we do is
we partner with the local utilities. So
they have excess power. They're not
monetizing. So I'll buy it right now.
I'll pay you your cost and I'll give you
two or 3/10 of a penny per kilowatt
hour. And and that that way the cities
make money whenever we're mining. So it
creates revenue for them by buying in
bulk or or increasing the consumption of
the community. It drives down the energy
prices for the local municipality for
the rateayers. then the sales tax that
you pay on that stays in the community.
So many of these small towns, not only
are we creating jobs, but they're
they're using the the the revenues that
come from Bitcoin mining profits to
build walking trails and splash pads and
park benches. There was even a story
done on the Atlanta news station that
the sales tax had created such a surplus
in some of these small communities that
they were paying people's property taxes
with the sales the surplus sales tax
generated from Clean Spark Mining. So we
we we feel like by partnering with the
utility, we can take that lowcost power
when it's available. And I think that's
what he meant when when you had the
interview is that there there's power
that isn't always consumed and if you
don't consume it, you lose it. It goes
to ground. You can't store it. It's not
efficient to build mega massive battery
facilities. So, think of a Bitcoin miner
as kind of a battery where they've
overbuilt generation to feed the massive
demand for AI, but when the AI isn't
demanding the power, you've got this
surplus capacity that has to go
somewhere. And Bitcoin mining is an
interruptible load. We can turn it off
and on. There's no memory on the A6. It
doesn't hurt them to curtail it. So, you
think of all the other industries, data
centers that host all the pictures on
Instagram or cold storage facilities or
a manufacturing facility. They can't
just shut down in the middle of their
process. Bitcoin mining is the perfect
partner for a utility because we can
interrupt. Hurricane hits Georgia, one
of the substations that feeds a little
town gets taken down. We have
infrastructure that we built that's
resilient and stronger. We shut down our
load, push the power back, the hospital
lights stay on. So, it really is the
perfect balance to a utility.
Um, I've met some miners from China and
they used to be the biggest mining
country, right? What is it like now? And
the profile seems very different.
>> Yeah. So, so China was had by far and
away the most hash rate in the world.
Um, when China banned Bitcoin mining a
number of years ago, a lot of that
migrated to the US because there are
these different utilities that have
abundant power. So think places like
Texas. So when that mining came offline
in China and it was banned, a lot of the
Chinese miners relocated to the US. And
so there, you know, they it trying to
duplicate the way that they're operated
in China. So you've got the the rainy
season and you rely heavily on
hydroelectric power. Hydroelectric power
is really abundant at times, almost
getting down to zero cost of power. The
US electrical grid doesn't quite work
the same. So we have peak and peak
demand which drives up energy costs. So
miners that were used to mining under
one set of utility rules in China then
come here and it's a it's an entirely
different dynamic. So we've we've been
fortunate to do some do business with a
number of different Chinese miners.
We've actually bought facilities from
Chinese miners. You know, one of the
things that's really unfortunate, um,
during the prior presidential
administration,
they were anti- Bitcoin, but they were
also concerned that Chinese Bitcoin
miners were a surveillance risk, which
is absolute nonsense. Bitcoin miners
don't have memory. They don't have
cameras. They don't have anything. So,
we bought a Bitcoin mining facility from
a Chinese company in Cheyenne, Wyoming.
And the prior president sent us a CPHASS
order. So, it's a committee for foreign
investment in the US and they literally
shut down our facility because they were
concerned that it was spying on the
United States. So,
>> what does that mean? They made us
>> Were you
the other the the the the Chinese minor
certainly wasn't? And we we bought the
facility and this is the kind of
nonsense that we dealt with in the prior
administration. Not only did they make
us tear down the facility and remove all
the transformers because they were
concerned about spyware and the
transformers. So got rid of all the
miners, got rid of all the power
distribution units, got rid of the
switch gear, the power supply units, the
transformers. They made us take down the
buildings. So then they sent out the
inspectors and they actually looked at
the concrete pads that were all that
remained and they suggested that we
should remove the concrete pads for fear
that there may be Chinese spyware buried
in the concrete. So you want to talk
about nonsense. So we, you know, we we
dealt with that. The new administration
is much much more friendly to Bitcoin.
Um and and we have some really
meaningful partnerships with uh mining
companies and suppliers from all over
Southeast Asia.
>> What is the relationship between moving
away from nonsense now? What is the
relationship between mining activity,
hash rate, and ultimately the Bitcoin
price?
>> It used to be more um but now it isn't.
I mean, you think about the fact that
there are 450 Bitcoin mined every day.
It doesn't matter what hash rate
difficulty is, what what hash rate and
hash price really impact is the
profitability of a Bitcoin miner.
Nothing to do with the price of Bitcoin.
So, the idea that there's a correlation
and at as an executive of a public
company, I get a lot of emails saying,
why are you guys manipulating the price
of Bitcoin? I only wish that we had that
much power.
>> Uh, one follow-up question. You said the
cost per Bitcoin is 42,42600
roughly. So
there is some
concern. We're not concerned, but some
people are wondering whether or not
that's the theoretical floor for Bitcoin
if the cost of Bitcoin for miners is a
consensus price range. So I'll give you
an example. So for gold mining for
example, if they're all in sustaining
costs somewhere, let's say $1,800 an
ounce, in theory, producers, large
producers would have less economic
incentive to produce and the supply of
gold would diminish and the market price
would go up. That's not exactly how it
works with Bitcoin. So
>> is there any relationship between your
cost per Bitcoin and the floor?
two epochs ago, so two having cycles
before when Bitcoin miners are producing
the vast majority of what's being
consumed. It I would say that Bitcoin
miners have an impact on the price to a
degree. The difference is the block
rewards are fixed. Every 10 minutes that
the block is audited and a new block
reward is made, those Bitcoin are issued
regardless of how many miners are on.
different from gold mining. If gold is
going up, I'm going to spend more money
on picks and shovels and put more guys
to work to mine more gold because there
is no cap on gold. Much the same with
oil. Oil prices go to $100 a barrel. All
of a sudden, more developers are
drilling oil wells because it's more
profitable. Oil's under pressure at $50
a barrel. People aren't m aren't aren't
drilling new wells. So, Bitcoin is
different because it's a fixed supply.
So if you think about econ 101, if
supply is tight and demand is high,
price goes up. So the the the the
challenge with Bitcoin is that the price
or the supply is fixed. So what we're
seeing is the volatility and demand. So
with the adoption of the ETFs, now
you've got all of this demand and the
ETFs have to buy the Bitcoin and hold it
in order to give you exposure. Just like
a gold ETF, if you invest in a gold ETF,
they have to actually own the gold
underlying that ETF. Same thing applies
to Bitcoin. So now you have this new
demand. You got Michael Sailor that's
now buying all the Bitcoin. You got
mining companies that are borrowing
billions of dollars to add Bitcoin to
their treasury. So you got this demand
that's skyrocketing. The reason we're
seeing volatility in the price of
Bitcoin, just my opinion, is that there
are still those people you you get the
gold bugs online and you get, you know,
some of the some of the analysts that
think Bitcoin is is magic internet
money. There's no real fundamental value
to it. First of all, they don't
understand proof of work. Um, and they
don't understand the way that Bitcoin is
is hardcaped. So, you have the perfect
currency in that it's it's peer-to-peer,
it's non non-s sovereign, it's
decentralized, it's hardcapped. Nobody,
there's no CEO of Bitcoin. Nobody can
change the rules and manipulate this.
So, it's it really does fulfill the
promise that was evidenced in Satoshi's
white paper, and that is that it's it's
a peer-to-peer cashless network for
anybody. So, it it allows the unbanked
to be banked. It it allows for all of
these benefits. Well, unfortunately,
there are still those that say Bitcoin
is fake. Bitcoin isn't real. There's no
fundamental value to Bitcoin. And as a
result, there are now opportunities or
investment products that you can buy
that short Bitcoin. So much the same as
you can buy a Bitcoin ETF that goes
long, you can buy a leverage short on
Bitcoin. So now you've got market
dynamics at work where you've got trades
where people are betting against
Bitcoin. So the beauty of that is that
now they're speculating that if Bitcoin
passes certain thresholds, there are
liquidations, forced liquidations
that'll take place that could drive the
price of Bitcoin parabolic. So, as an
executive of a public company, I can't
comment on my own stock price, but I can
tell you that I firmly believe that
Bitcoin will exceed $200,000 this year.
>> Wow.
>> I forgot what I was going to ask because
I was not expecting a price prediction.
Thank you. Wow.
>> Two, let's talk about it. 200K. What's
your thesis there?
>> Supply and demand.
>> Okay.
>> You look at the consumption that's
taking place. So Jack Mers is leading
the new um Bitcoin. Yeah. 21 Capital um
through a caner spa. Um they're talking
about raising money to buy Bitcoin. Uh
just yesterday there was an announcement
that Trump Media is doing a $3 billion
raise to buy Bitcoin. So what we've
already established in this chat is that
there are only 450 new Bitcoin a day. So
with that much demand pent up on the
network and supply being fixed, you
can't doesn't matter if Bitcoin goes to
300,000. We can't mine more than 450
Bitcoin a day no matter what. So the the
supply shock in my mind is what's really
going to drive that next phase.
Historically there have been cycles,
right? So the having cycle, Bitcoin runs
up, having happens, the price pulls
back. I mean, we saw what, November of
21, it's 69,000. You get midway through
22, it's 15,000.
I think with the adoption of the ETFs
and the increase in demand, especially
these new Bitcoin treasury companies,
the idea that there's going to be that
that demand is going to wayne and price
is going to be depressed. I don't think
it's realistic anymore. I think that
cycle has been broken and I think we're
now in price discovery. this this
Bitcoin conference being held right now
as Bitcoin is hitting all-time highs
with all these very credible I mean
goodness gracious um Howard Lutnik who
sits in the in in the cabinet is the
founder of Caner Fitzgerald and Caner is
the the spa partner with Jack Mer's new
company so we have Bitcoin advocates at
the highest level of our government and
now what we're seeing is nation states
are procuring and acquiring Bitcoin for
strategic reserves we We know it's
happening in the Middle East. We know
it's begun to happen in China. We know
that there the the accumulation of
Bitcoin has started at a meaningful
level. And with supply as fixed as it
is, it can only have one impact on
price.
>> I think this echo backs to my first
question, which is miners hold absolute
power over the Bitcoin price. Meaning
you said there are only 450 Bitcoin
mined a day. What you can do is I'll
just hold it.
>> Yeah.
>> You guys want to buy, I'll hold it.
>> Yeah. So theoretically that would be
true, but when you talk about the the
the fact that it's now a multi-trillion
dollar industry,
450 Bitcoin isn't a drop in a bucket. If
we held all of the Bitcoin production,
it wouldn't have any impact because
Michael Sailor is buying 500,000 Bitcoin
at a time, right? I mean, the the idea
that all of the miners in the world, so
CleanSpark is we we have the most hash
rate in of anyone in the United States.
We're the second biggest minor in the
world and we comprise about 5% of the
global hash rate. So to think all of the
Bitcoin miners are going to get together
and say, "Okay guys, on three we're
going to hold all the Bitcoin and and we
could do that." It wouldn't make a hill
of beans for a difference because this
the demand the the 20 million Bitcoin
that are already out daily production
has no impact on price.
Just following up on that, the other
side of the equation, let's suppose
Bitcoin miners were to go offline
tomorrow, either by government decree as
was the case in China or they go
bankrupt. I'm not saying, you guys are
doing fine, but just in theory, they go
offline. What would happen to the
treasury? Would there not be a huge
liquidation event?
>> So, the problem is that in order to sell
or buy Bitcoin, you have to have miners.
Miners validate each block. So without
Bitcoin mining, Bitcoin doesn't exist.
So it can't, you know, it's
decentralized and it's non-s sovereign.
So there's Bitcoin mining in South
America, Central America, North America,
all over Asia, all over Europe, Bitcoin
mining everywhere. So to think that, you
know, there would be a stroke of a pen
that would ban Bitcoin mining globally
isn't realistic.
>> But let's say, let's say if Clean Spark
were to pack up shop tomorrow for
whatever reason, not just not just by a
banned degree, what would happen to your
treasury?
Nothing. I mean, but we would still I
mean, if we're talking theoretically,
the Bitcoin doesn't go away. We we hold
that Bitcoin um off.
>> You offload it to to the market though.
>> Um
I I can't imagine that part of your
liquidation event. Yeah.
>> Yeah. There's there I can tell you
there's there's no plans for any kind of
liquidation. Sure.
>> And our Bitcoin treasury is going
nowhere but up.
>> All right.
>> I want to ask you about the four-year
cycle. So for an average person that are
not very familiar with how it works um
the analogy they'll use is okay if you
say Bitcoin is this digital building
then miners would be the construction
workers or the construction company. Now
if I go and tell you or I pitch this
oldw world construction company say hey
build this building it's going to make
you a lot of money the value is going to
go up. However, in every four years, the
revenue is going to be cut in half. Then
in the old world, they'll think it's
crazy. But somehow this works in
Bitcoin. Why?
>> That's a great question. Um, so you
think about every block is 10 minutes,
right? So four having cycles ago it was
50 Bitcoin a block and then it went to
25 after the having and then it went to
12 a.5 and then 6.25 and now 3.125. So
difficulty is going up through those
having cycles. What that does is it
makes if there if you if you get 50
Bitcoin every 10 minutes and Bitcoin is
priced like it is now you're you're
you're a fat cat, right? You got you got
all you need.
The design of the system
is is is set up to create scarcity.
It's also set up to drive efficiency.
So, Bitcoin mining companies that don't
have good cost of power, that don't have
good infrastructure, that don't have
efficient AS6, that don't have high
uptime can't compete in a market
environment where the margins get
squeezed. So we're making 23 24 bitcoin
a day right now. Prior to having we were
making 23 or 24 bitcoin. So CleanSpark
has continued to invest not only in a
new infrastructure, new facilities, new
equipment, but also investing in
efficiencies,
increasing the value of our operations,
decreasing our input costs to make us
more profitable. During that period of
time, we've acquired a lot of other
miners that can't compete because
they're not as efficient. So, we have
the benefit of scale. We've achieved
what we like to call exit velocity. That
is, we can continue to grow and thrive
and build regardless of the other
inputs, access to equity or debt
capital. We can self- sustain on the
Bitcoin that we mine, which makes us
very dangerous. I don't have to go out
and raise money in order to compete with
my peers. So if the market is under
pressure and share prices are down, now
all of a sudden they're looking for
alternative strategies to make money. So
less efficient on Bitcoin miners, now
you're hearing a lot about HPC and AI.
It just so happens that the miners that
are focusing on that are the same miners
that have less efficient fleets. So I
think there's a correlation.
I
>> think that about does it. Thank you very
much, Matt.
>> Thank you so much for having me. This
has been a lot of fun.
>> Yeah, I appreciate your time.
>> Absolutely. Pleasure to meet you.
>> I think everybody's going to love this.